<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-12-05T20:39:41</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-12-05T22:06:42</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="32_letras_portugues_ingles-24.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="145,299 317,299 317,359 1601,359 1601,1028 1599,1028 1599,1081 1488,1081 1488,1645 144,1645 144,359 145,359"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96671">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 24
Language teachers are often frustrated by the fact that students do not automatically transfer the strategies
they use when reading in their native language to reading in a language they are learning. Instead, they seem
to think reading means starting at the beginning and going word by word, stopping to look up every unknown
vocabulary item, until they reach the end. When they do this, students are relying exclusively on their linguistic
knowledge, a bottom-up strategy. One of the most important functions of language teachers, then, is to
help students move past this idea and use top-down strategies as they do in their native language. Effective
teachers show students how they can adjust their reading behavior to deal with a variety of situations, types
of input, and reading purposes. They help students develop a set of reading strategies and match appropriate
strategies to each reading situation. Some of these strategies are previewing, predicting, skimming, scanning,
and paraphrasing texts. They include reviewing titles, section headings, and photo captions to get a sense of
the structure and content of a reading selection; using knowledge of the subject matter to make predictions
about content and vocabulary and check comprehension; using knowledge of the text type and the author
to make predictions about writing style, vocabulary, and content; making a quick survey of the text to get
the main idea, confirm or question predictions; guessing prior knowledge of the subject and the ideas in the
text as clues to the meanings of unknown words; stopping at the end of a section to check comprehension
by restating the information and ideas in the text. When language learners use reading strategies, they find
that they can control the reading experience, and they gain confidence in their ability to read the language.
Disponível em: &lt;http://www.nclrc.org&gt;. Acesso em: 29 jul. 2014 (adaptado).
Taking into account the reading strategies mentioned in the text, consider the following statements.
|. Skimming means to glance at the text to find the desired information.
Il. Paraphrasing refers to the reproduction of the content of a given text.
Ill. Scanning means to read a text quickly in search of its general idea.
IV. Previous knowledge refers to the knowledge accumulated from one's personal experience.
Itis only correct what is stated on
o.
o.
O Iandill.
O ll and Iv.
O ll andiv.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
