<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-12-05T20:40:30</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-12-05T22:09:09</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="32_letras_portugues_ingles-20.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="145,299 316,299 316,364 1600,364 1600,756 1601,756 1601,1011 1599,1011 1599,1400 1600,1400 1600,1473 1599,1473 1599,1573 1598,1573 1598,1670 597,1670 597,1730 348,1730 348,2001 146,2001 146,1758 147,1758 147,1701 192,1701 192,1595 194,1595 194,1498 240,1498 240,1377 195,1377 195,1376 194,1376 194,1279 146,1279 146,1278 145,1278 145,1143 146,1143 146,1144 588,1144 588,1011 145,1011 145,1010 144,1010 144,364 145,364"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.93928">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 19
The world is changing -- it is getting both smaller and bigger at the same time. Our world shrinks as
technologies now allow us to communicate both synchronously and asynchronously with peers around the
world. Conversely, the explosion of information now available to us expands our view of the world. As a result
of the ability to communicate globally and the information explosion, education must change.
The current teaching paradigm of the teacher as the possessor and transferor of information is shifting to
a new paradigm of the teacher as a facilitator or coach. This new teacher will provide contextual learning
environments that engage students in collaborative activities that will require communications and access to
information that only technology can provide.
Unfortunately, we don't have to look hard to find teachers utilizing new technological tools to replicate old
educational models. For example, most uses of distance education employ the same instructor delivering
the same lecture to the same audience, only now the audience can be larger. This distance education model
does nothing to address the concept of lifelong learning. This traditional model still places the student in
a passive role, merely absorbing as much information as possible. Instead, more collaborative models of
distance education could be employed.
MOLEBASH P. Technology and Education: Current and Future Trends. Disponível em: &lt;www.itari.in&gt;.
Acesso em: 22 jul. 2014 (adaptado).
According to the text, consider the following statements.
|. New technologies help students to interact with each other simultaneously; however, educators have
not adapted to the new learning environment yet.
Il. Information technology provides educators with new tools, as video conferencing, so that they are
able to deliver lectures to larger audiences, what enhances learning.
III.New technologies allow educators to create situations in which students have contact with other
cultures, learn about other realities, interact and share knowledge.
IV. Contextual learning environments guided by educators and assisted by information technology help
students to engage in exchanging of experiences and developing critical thinking.
V. Internet helps more students to absorb information. The educators' role is to provide students with
the appropriate learning environment to acquire this information.
Itis only correct what is stated on
O 1,1 and Iv.
O LIlandv.
O 1, and Iv.
O 1, Il and v.
O UI, IVandv.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
