<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-12-05T20:41:24</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-12-05T22:12:37</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="32_letras_portugues_ingles-15.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<ImageRegion id="r1">
	<Coords points="143,347 142,776 1601,779 1602,350"/></ImageRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="145,299 316,299 316,836 594,836 594,896 858,896 858,996 1550,996 1550,1412 1599,1412 1599,1434 1598,1434 1598,1542 1248,1542 1248,1747 1246,1747 1246,1795 146,1795 146,1542 145,1542 145,1477 191,1477 191,996 195,996 195,331 146,331 146,330 145,330"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96002">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 13
Friday 13 June 2014 at 6.30pm
Maths Lecture Theatre,
School of Mathematical Sciences, Mile End Campus
The talk aims to provide a holistic sociohistorical, political as well as linguistic account of the process by
wich a new English emerges in a colonial environment. Taking the case of the Republic of Palau in
Micronesia as an example, | will examine, first, the emergence of English in the context of the country's
complex colonial past.
Second, | attempt to apply Schneider's “Dynamic Model' of postcolonial English formation to this
community. Palau provides an interesting and important testing ground for the model, because few
communities in which English has emerged as a result of American as opposed to British colonialism have
been examined to date. Finally, | present, based on analyses of recordings of informal conversations
among Palauans, an initial portrait of the main linguistic characteristics of Paluan English, and assess the
extent to which English is nativising in this small community.
Disponível em: &lt;http://linguistics-research-digest.blogspot.com.br&gt;. Acesso em: 15 jul. 2014 (adaptado).
If a foreign language teacher attends the lecture by David Britain, its subject might help him/her prepare a
class about
O language variation, dialects and “Englishes”.
O lexical similarities and differences between world Englishes.
O grammatical aspects of the English language used by non-native speakers.
O differences between American and British English variations around the world.
O dialects of the English language as a mother tongue and as a foreign language.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
