<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-10-28T11:59:04</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-10-28T12:09:38</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="08_MEDICINA-16.jpg" imageWidth="1614" imageHeight="2168">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="81,235 252,235 252,295 1536,295 1536,602 1535,602 1535,1281 1534,1281 1534,1391 1535,1391 1535,1551 83,1551 83,1552 82,1552 82,980 80,980 80,295 81,295"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95931">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 20
While the term epigenetics is often used loosely, and sometimes in rather different ways, the term is
generally considered to encompass changes in DNA methylation, histone modifications, miRNA expression,
and nucleo-some positioning and higher order chromatin as epigenetic changes affecting gene regulation.
Epigenetics was defined as a discipline more than 50 years ago, by CH Waddington, and originally described
changes in the development of organisms that could not be explained by changes in DNA. Subsequently it
became clear that epigenetic modifications play important roles in diseases, including breast cancer. There
is thus a pressing need to understand the functional genome; that is, the changes defined by regulatory
mechanisms overlaying the genetic structure.
Over the past few years there has been an explosion in studies of epigenetics in breast cancer, reflected
by the exponential increase of published manuscripts. A PubMed search for the keywords “epigenetic'
and “breast cancer' reveals that the first publication was in 1983. Progress was slow until approximately
10 years ago when the number of studies started to steadily increase, at least in part fueled by improved
technologies. In the present review, we focus on recent advances in the understanding of histone methylation
and demethylation, a relatively new area with promise for clinical translation. We also review recent studies
that have utilized genome-wide technologies for the study of DNA methylation. Much progress has been
made in the characterization of noncoding RNAs, and the effect of higher order chromatin structure on gene
expression in breast cancer; however, these discoveries lie outside the scope of our review.
Breast Cancer Res. 2011; 13(6): 225.
De acordo com o texto acima, epigenética é uma
O alteração gênica decorrente da mudança da estrutura do DNA, sem aumento de publicações a seu respeito
nos últimos anos.
O alteração das características determinadas geneticamente, com aumento das publicações a seu respeito
nos últimos anos.
O alteração gênica decorrente da mudança de RNAm, sem aumento significativo de publicações a seu
respeito nos últimos anos.
O alteração gênica decorrente da mudança de RNAm, com aumento de interesse a seu respeito em citações
de revistas nos últimos 50 anos.
O alteração gênica decorrente da mudança da estrutura da proteína do DNA, com aumento de citações a
seu respeito em revistas médicas, nos últimos anos.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
