<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:10:47</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:47:00</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-34.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 340,244 340,312 1576,312 1576,852 1575,852 1575,1011 1576,1011 1576,1271 1575,1271 1575,1344 1340,1344 1340,1486 1438,1486 1438,1567 1180,1567 1180,1614 763,1614 763,1662 171,1662 171,1663 170,1663 170,1408 168,1408 168,1378 263,1378 263,1271 218,1271 218,1141 219,1141 219,1012 218,1012 218,985 169,985 169,854 168,854 168,448 169,448"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95422">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 30
In the fall of 1999, Allyson Young, a high school English teacher in Charlottesville, Virginia, was having
difficulty teaching writing with two of her applied level ninth-grade English classes. In addition to her
students struggling with fluency and poor writing skills, they posed behavior problems for each other.
Through a partnership with the English Education program at the University of Virginia, Young began to
use an online portfolio tool with the students in this particular class to facilitate the teaching of writing
and enhance the writing process and writing workshop. In addition to the excitement and enthusiasm
the students expressed for being able to pilot new technology and to use the school's computer lab, they
also responded by successfully engaging in drafting, conferencing, revising, editing, and publishing their
writing.
The focus was now on the writing rather than cutting each other down. Students began to consistently
get writing down on paper and complete drafts. Fluency was a major problem, but their fluency improved
over time with the online feedback they were receiving from their peers. Their drafts not only became
longer, but they improved in terms of content and quality too.
YOUNG, C. A.; BUSH, J. Teaching the English language arts with technology: a critical approach and pedagogical framework.
Contemporary Issues in Technology and Teacher Education, v. 4, n.1, p. 1-22, 2004 (adaptado).
Considerando o texto apresentado, avalie as asserções a seguir e a relação proposta entre elas.
|. O caso relatado motiva os professores a estarem em constante processo de avaliação, tanto da
aprendizagem do aluno quanto de sua prática pedagógica, para que possam fazer intervenções
por meio do ensino.
PORQUE
Ill. O feedback da professora, por meio da correção dos textos de cada aluno, contribuiu
significativamente para o aprimoramento da escrita dos alunos, demonstrando que a constatação
de um problema em sala de aula deve ser o ponto de partida em busca de opções para
solucioná-lo.
A respeito dessas asserções, assinale a opção correta.
O As asserções | e |l são proposições verdadeiras, e a Il é uma justificativa correta da |.
O As asserções | e Il são proposições verdadeiras, mas a Il não é uma justificativa correta da |.
O A asserção | é uma proposição verdadeira, e a Il é uma proposição falsa.
O A asserção | é uma proposição falsa, e a |l é uma proposição verdadeira.
O As asserções | e II são proposições falsas.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
