<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:11:38</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:49:24</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-30.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<SeparatorRegion id="r1">
	<Coords points="872,246 872,2112 873,2112 873,246"/></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r12" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 339,244 339,316 856,316 856,517 854,517 854,1439 855,1439 855,2015 853,2015 853,2104 169,2104 169,1405 168,1405 168,1332 215,1332 215,517 168,517 168,316 169,316"/>
	<ImageRegion id="r3">
	<Coords points="152,661 152,1300 847,1300 847,661"/></ImageRegion>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96119">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 25
Action Research is a disciplined process of
inquiry conducted by and for those taking the
action. The primary reason for engaging in Action
Research is to assist the “actor” in improving
and/or redefining his or her actions.
SAGOR, R. Guiding School Improvement with Action Research.
Alexandria: ASCD, 2000. Available at: &lt;http://www.ascd.org&gt;.
Access on: Jul. 16th 2017 (adapted).
Considering the text and the image above, choose
the correct option.
O The action taken in this type of research is
an intervention that will be later assessed in
terms of effectiveness through observation and
reflection.
O In action research applied to the classroom, the
“actor” is the student, and the research aims to
improve his/her actions.
O Action research is linear and, therefore, ends
when the practice of the actor becomes
statistically improved.
O Due to its qualitative nature, action research
is conducted informally and lacks specific
techniques.
O Action research is a rigorous research method
unsuitable for classsoom environment.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r18" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="890,244 1061,244 1061,314 1577,314 1577,798 1576,798 1576,1528 1578,1528 1578,1598 1576,1598 1576,2103 891,2103 891,1528 902,1528 902,1393 889,1393 889,314 890,314"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96424">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 26
Many students having difficulty understanding
Shakespeare would be surprised to learn that he
wrote in Modern English, but Elizabethan English
has much more in common with our language
today than it does with the language of Chaucer.
Many familiar words and phrases were coined
or first recorded by Shakespeare. Newcomers to
Shakespeare are often shocked at the number
of clichés contained in his plays, until they realize
that he coined them and they became clichés
afterwards. "One fell swoop," "vanish into thin air,"
and "flesh and blood" are all Shakespeare's.
One major factor which influenced the language
and served to separate Middle and Modern
English was the Great Vowel Shift, a change in
pronunciation that began around 1400. While
Modern English speakers can read Chaucer with
some difficulty, Chaucer's pronunciation would
have been completely unintelligible to the modern
ear. Shakespeare, on the other hand, would be
accented, but understandable. Vowel sounds began
to be made further to the front of the mouth and
the letter "e" at the end of words became silent.
Chaucer's Lyf (pronounced "leef") became the
modern life. In Middle English, five was pronounced
"feef", and down was pronounced "doon'".
Available at: &lt;http://www.anglik.net/englishlanguagehistory.htm&gt;.
Access on: Jul. 19th 2017 (adapted).
Considering the excerpt above about the history of
English, choose the correct option.
O Chaucer's English was influenced by the Great
Vowel Shift.
O “One fell swoop” is an example of a cliché used
in English during Chaucer's time.
O The examples used to explain the Great Vowel
Shift show that long vowels became diphthongs.
O Chaucer and Shakespeare are two writers who
produced English literature at the same period.
O It would be easier to listen to Chaucer's English
than to Shakespearean English due to the Great
Vowel Shift.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
