<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:15:08</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T19:00:54</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-13.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r26" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,322 513,322 513,390 1576,390 1576,755 1575,755 1575,1056 1315,1056 1315,897 992,897 992,1001 219,1001 219,1000 218,1000 218,897 170,897 170,896 169,896 169,754 168,754 168,390 169,390"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96435">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO DISCURSIVA 03
The Bronté sisters, Charlotte, Emily and Anne Brontê, not only contributed much to the growth of the
novel, but also to the position of women at their time. They did much to alter the way in which women
were viewed. Like George Eliot, however, they adopted pseudonyms in order not to draw attention to the
fact that they were women.
The third sister, Anne, wrote The Tenant of Wildfell Hall (1848), which has been overshadowed by
Charlotte and Emily's more spectacular successes. It is, however, an important novel in its own right. In
the novel Anne Brontê depicts a bitterly unhappy marriage followed by the departure of the wife, Helen
Huntingdon, and her search for new freedom. One critic wrote that "the slamming of Helen's bedroom
door against her husband reverberated throughout Victorian England."
MCRAE, J.; CARTER, R. The Routledge History of Literature in English. London: Routledge, 2001 (adaptado).
Considerando as informações apresentadas, redija um texto acerca da escrita de autoria feminina na
Inglaterra do século XIX, abordando os seguintes aspectos:
* a condição da mulher burguesa no século XIX;
* a produção literária de autoria feminina no século XIX.
(valor: 10,0 pontos)</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
