<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:13:35</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:57:10</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-21.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 339,244 339,314 1576,314 1576,1082 1575,1082 1575,1302 1576,1302 1576,1376 1575,1376 1575,1740 170,1740 170,1268 169,1268 169,1198 288,1198 288,1082 168,1082 168,804 169,804"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96074">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 15
During an American Literature survey course at an American university, there was a racial incident at the
university library. It was bad enough to make the President of the university send a message condemning
racism and improper behavior, and to lead many African American students hold protests and marches
On campus.
In the final exam period, the professor responsible for the survey course exhorted students that such
incidents show why we need to study literature, specifically literature of diverse voices from the past. He
mentioned some texts which directly addressed white readership about the hypocrisy of racial bias, as a
prime example of the type of literary work that the offending student, and all students, should be reading
so as to interrogate critically their own prejudices and to nullify or respond thoughtfully to such hateful
acts. He also encouraged them to be activists in addition to scholars, to speak up against injustice while
remembering the lessons of earlier American culture wars.
As the ensuing final project presentations demonstrated, he needn't have bothered. The class had already
internalized these lessons and applied them to their anthology and literary recovery projects. These
projects recovered forgotten or neglected voices and put them into conversation with our world of 2015
or grouped together activist or subversive texts from American writers. Regardless of the topics they
chose, these students were making pre-1900 American literature speak to their time as well as to its own.
In essence, this was the entire point of the survey course, which, throughout the semester, worked to
surface issues of canon: who's in, who's out, and who decides, at what points in history.
THOMPSON, T.; TONTI, K. American Literature Time Machine: Toward a Democratic Canon in the Undergraduate Survey Course.
American Literature: A Journal of Theory and Practice, v. 8, n. 4, p. 14-38, 2017 (adaptado).
Segundo esse texto, o professor de literatura norte-americana repensou o currículo e a sua prática na sala
de aula a partir de um incidente ocorrido na universidade onde leciona. A proposta do professor foi
O estudar em suas aulas de literatura as obras de autores norte-americanos que tratassem do tema do
preconceito racial.
O apresentar a seus alunos as obras canônicas da literatura norte-americana para que pudessem
conhecer a cultura daquele país.
O concentrar-se na leitura de autores oitocentistas norte-americanos que tratassem de ativismo
social contra a questão do racismo.
O trabalhar com a internalização do conteúdo das suas aulas de literatura norte-americana para que se
saíssem melhor em seus projetos sociais.
O resgatar obras e autores do passado que dialogassem com questões socioculturais atuais e cuja leitura
levasse a questionamentos críticos acerca de posicionamentos preconceituosos do presente.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
