<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:14:50</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T19:00:18</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-15.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r25" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 513,244 513,312 1578,312 1578,581 1577,581 1577,797 1576,797 1576,1059 169,1059 169,797 168,797 168,312 169,312"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.87961">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO DISCURSIVA 05
Technological innovations have changed language learning radically from the old-fashioned image of
pupils learning lists of verbs out of textbooks. Although language teaching has a long history of using
tech, dating back to the 1960s, recent developments such as social networking and easy-to-use video
cameras have removed many of the limitations. Whereas using tech may have once meant a weekly trip
to a computer lab, it can now involve anything, from social media to podcasts and videos in the classroom.
The question is: should teachers try to evolve their teaching to fit with the latest gadgets, or should they
stick to their old ways?
Those who use tech say the advantages are obvious. A linguistics lecturer at Warwick and founder
of a teacher training website, says that languages and digital technology are a natural fit. "Language
developmentis around four skills — reading, writing, speaking and listening — and all of those are facilitated
by technology. There's a very strong link between the affordances of technology and the type of things
we're trying to do as teachers."
Disponível em: &lt;http://www.theguardian.com&gt;. Acesso em: 16 jul. 2017 (adaptado).
Considerando o excerto apresentado, redija um texto sobre o uso de tecnologias digitais em aulas de inglês
da educação básica. Em seu texto, discuta como as habilidades de ler, escrever, falar e escutar podem
ser praticadas de forma integrada por meio de tecnologias digitais e exemplifique como as tecnologias
digitais podem beneficiar o processo de ensino e aprendizagem da língua inglesa na educação básica, no
espaço escolar e extra-escolar. (valor: 10,0 pontos)</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
