<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:12:25</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:55:04</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-26.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 339,244 339,360 1578,360 1578,510 1575,510 1575,1449 1576,1449 1576,1808 610,1808 610,1863 360,1863 360,2117 170,2117 170,1808 169,1808 169,1528 168,1528 168,1448 169,1448 169,834 168,834 168,509 167,509 167,360 169,360"/>
	<ImageRegion id="r1">
	<Coords points="500,930 500,1480 1572,1480 1572,930"/></ImageRegion>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.89868">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 21
TEXT1
So why does this matter for the english as a second language (ESL) teacher? Because podcasts are a great
resource for your classroom. You can use podcasts lots of different ways to help your students in their
journey to learn English. And there's one other great reason teachers love podcasts. They're FREE! So if
you want to learn how to use podcasts with your ESL students, here are some thoughts on how to do that.
Available at: &lt;http://busyteacher.org/22450-podcasts-esl-classroom-top-9-ways.html&gt;. Access on: Jul. 5th 2017 (adapted).
TEXT 2
Hear something you like and think other people will like it too? You can share podcasts to social media and
more! You can share the podcast itself or individual episodes.
Launch the podcasts app from your home screen. Tap the podcast or episode you'd like to share.
Tap the share button. It's a box with an upward arrow. Tap the method you'd like to use to share the
podcast or episode. Share as you would normally.
Available at: &lt;https://www.imore.com/apple-podcasts&gt;. Access on: Jul. 5th 2017 (adapted).
TEXT3
Available at: &lt;http://www.glasbergen.com&gt;. Access on: Jul. 5th 2017 (adapted).
Analyze the following statements regarding the texts above.
|. Texts of the same genre as text 3 are meant to entertain through humor while expressing social
criticism.
Il. Text 1 can be classified as persuasive, because the author tries to convince the reader to adopt
their position on an issue.
Ill. The purpose of text 2 is to encourage or persuade teachers to create their own podcasts.
IV. Understanding textual genres is important for students to learn from what they read.
Itis only correct what is stated in
O landll.
O ll and!ll.
O ll andiv.
O 1,1 and Iv.
O 1,11 and |v.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
