<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:12:04</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:50:09</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-28.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="170,244 340,244 340,314 1578,314 1578,733 1577,733 1577,999 1576,999 1576,1411 1396,1411 1396,1511 170,1511 170,999 169,999 169,314 170,314"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95541">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 23
Some literary theory has indeed been excessively in-group and obscurantist, and this book represents one
attempt to undo that damage and make it more widely accessible. But there is another sense in which
such theory is the very reverse of elitist. What is truly elitist in literary studies is the idea that works of
literature can only be appreciated by those with a particular sort of cultural breeding. There are those
who have literary values in their bones, and those who languish in the outer darkness.
One important reason for the growth of literary theory since the 1960s was the gradual breakdown of
this assumption, under the impact of new kinds of students entering higher education from supposedly
'uncultivated' backgrounds. Theory was a way of emancipating literary works from the stranglehold of a
'civilized sensibility', and throwing them open to a kind of analysis in which, in principle at least, anyone
could participate.
Those who complain of the difficulty of such theory would often, ironically enough, not expect to
understand a textbook of biology or chemical engineering straight off. Why then should literary studies
be any different? Perhaps because we expect literature itself to be an 'ordinary' kind of language instantly
available to everyone; but this is itself a very particular 'theory' of literature. Properly understood, literary
theoryis shaped by a democratic impulse rather than an elitist one; and to this extent, when it does lapse
into the turgidly unreadable, it is being untrue to its own historical roots.
EAGLETON, T. Literary Theory: an introduction. Minneapolis: The University of Minnesota Press, 1996 (adaptado).
Segundo o texto, o crescimento da área da teoria literária deve-se
O à tentativa de desfazer os prejuízos originados por algumas correntes da teoria literária
excessivamente endógenas e obscuras.
O à crescente facilidade da linguagem dos textos de teoria literária em comparação com a dificuldade
dos de outras áreas do saber.
O ao rompimento paulatino com a ideia de literatura limitada aos que possuem grande sensibilidade e
valores literários de berço.
O ao acesso à alta cultura por parte dos alunos universitários de diferentes classes sociais.
O ao caráter emancipatório das teorias surgidas a partir dos anos 1960.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
