<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:13:51</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:57:42</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-20.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 340,244 340,317 1576,317 1576,1001 1578,1001 1578,1389 1576,1389 1576,1562 1574,1562 1574,1684 1576,1684 1576,1713 939,1713 939,1855 1228,1855 1228,1908 1277,1908 1277,1993 1033,1993 1033,2046 771,2046 771,2098 170,2098 170,2047 169,2047 169,1790 218,1790 218,1684 263,1684 263,1562 218,1562 218,1502 169,1502 169,1390 168,1390 168,844 169,844"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95953">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 14
| am an American with a difference: | work at the most British of institutions, the BBC. Generally, as an
analyst of U.S. affairs, my American accent is an advantage, lending a kind of authenticity to my words.
But there are times when my voice ruffles feathers. This happened to me for the first time while recording
a programme last year, when through the studio window | saw my producer wince. "Il think you've
mispronounced something", she said rather tentatively from the control booth. | asked if | had run out
of breath at the end of the sentence. Or did | pop a "p" or whistle through an "s"? But my responses only
seemed to annoy her. "No, nothing like that", she sniffed. "It's in the last paragraph, the word 'schedule'".
It sounded, well, quite American."
Being an American, | pronounced the word with a hard "k": S-K-E-D-U-L-E. | was about to suggest we
change the script to read "timetable" or "plan", when my producer put forward a suggestion of her own.
"Let's try that paragraph again, shall we, with the word schedule pronounced correctly!"
It seemed to me that by insinuating my pronunciation was wrong, rather than simply different, my
producer had crossed a line. This was now a question of right and wrong, of whether an American — any
American — is capable of speaking the English language properly without faking an Oxbridge accent.
"| don't think it's actually wrong to say it this way", | ventured. "Wouldn't | sound ridiculous with my
American accent saying schedule the British way?" She was ready for me. "Absolutely not. One should
never be afraid to be correct." By now, the studio manager and producer's assistant were listening intently.
My etymology lesson continued: "The 'sch' sound comes from German", my producer said, "as in Schultz
or schnitzel." "| suppose you learned that in schule", | said sarcastically. The studio manager, an Irishman,
let out a little laugh which was cut short by the producer's sharp gaze. "We are wasting time here", she
correctly observed. "Let's move on." Like most linguistic battles between English-speaking peoples, this
one ended inconclusively, with both sides agreeing essentially to disagree. (| said "timetable" instead of
"schedule").
MORAN, M. Listen, you guys, it's my language, too! In: Speak Up. São Paulo, ed. 101, Aug. 1995 (adapted).
Taking the text above into account, analyze the following statements and the relationship between them.
|. The text depicts a situation in which a speaker of a non British variation of the English language is
criticized for using his own language, when it was expected from him to speak with a British accent.
BECAUSE
Il. The British producer acted as a "guardian" of the English language according to a false belief in one
unique correct linguistic variation.
Considering these statements, choose the correct option.
O Statements | and || are true propositions, and Il is a correct justification of |.
O Statements | and || are true propositions, but Il is not a correct justification of |.
O Statement | is a true proposition, and Il is a false proposition.
O Statement lis a false proposition, and Il is a true proposition.
O Sstatements | and Il are false propositions.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
