<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:12:40</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:55:26</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-25.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="170,244 341,244 341,360 1577,360 1577,510 1576,510 1576,821 1578,821 1578,1129 1577,1129 1577,1130 1576,1130 1576,1287 1426,1287 1426,1432 1576,1432 1576,1402 1576,1432 668,1432 668,1487 335,1487 335,1740 170,1740 170,1518 172,1518 172,1432 218,1432 218,1231 171,1231 171,1130 170,1130 170,1129 169,1129 169,1128 170,1128 170,796 169,796 169,722 170,722 170,509 169,509 169,314 170,314"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95582">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 20
TEXTO 1
Technology is a tool. It's not a learning outcome. Too often do we get distracted by all the activities and
actions we can perform with a tablet or some other device. They are all exciting things, to be sure. But
these are not actually learning outcomes. You could have a 1:1 tablet classsoom where your students
create a bazillion (it's a word, | swear) presentations all about how much they're learning.
But they're not really learning. They're using a device.
Don't get me wrong, you can do a lot of good with technology in the classroom. That's the whole reason
edtech sites exist. But technology is a tool that's meant to be added to your toolbox just like anything else.
It may be a powerful tool, but it's a tool nonetheless.
Disponível em: &lt;http://appliedsciencesfoundation.org/&gt;. Acesso em: 15 jul. 2017 (adaptado).
TEXTO 2
Educational applications let students experience a new learning culture. The teacher is no longer the
sole, mono-directional provider of knowledge. Rather, they play the role of an equal participant within
a community of practice; everybody can learn from their peers within the context of Web 2.0 scenarios.
By constantly communicating and collaborating with other group members, everyone will automatically
get reflective input and feedback on their english as a foreign language (EFL) performance. Many Web 2.0
apps support democratic learning settings where students form an intensive collaboration with their
teacher or, even better, with a coach. This more egalitarian learning environment usually generates a very
positive attitude towards learning a language.
STRASSER, T. Mind the app!: inspiring internet tools and activities to engage your students. Rum: Helbling Languages, 2012 (adaptado).
Em relação a esse tema, avalie as afirmações a seguir, a respeito das ideias expressas nos dois textos.
|. Cadatexto atribui papéis diferentes ao professor no contexto de uso de tecnologia na aprendizagem.
Il. As ferramentas tecnológicas são mais valorizadas do que o processo de aprendizagem.
Ill. A tecnologia pode ser útil no processo de aprendizagem.
IV. O professor deve ser tecnicamente treinado para o uso de tecnologias.
É correto apenas o que se afirma em
Oie.
Oem.
O eiv.
O L1lelv.
OQ, Meiv.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
