<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-28T05:11:10</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-28T18:48:23</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="29_LET_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-32.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="170,244 341,244 341,973 1577,973 1577,1114 1578,1114 1578,1351 1577,1351 1577,1769 1439,1769 1439,1991 1188,1991 1188,2040 764,2040 764,2090 171,2090 171,2091 170,2091 170,1827 169,1827 169,1114 171,1114 171,275 170,275"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95928">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 28
Krashen's theory of second language acquisition consists of five main hypotheses: the Acquisition-Learning
hypothesis, the Monitor hypothesis, the Input hypothesis, the Natural Order hypothesis, and the Affective
Filter hypothesis.
The Affective Filter hypothesis, embodies Krashen's view that a number of “affective variables” play a
facilitative, but non-causal, role in second language acquisition. These variables include: motivation, self-
confidence and anxiety. Krashen claims that learners with high motivation, self-confidence, a good self-
image, and a low level of anxiety are better equipped for success in second language acquisition. Low
motivation, low self-esteem, and debilitating anxiety can combine to “raise” the affective filter and form
a “mental block” that prevents comprehensible input from being used for acquisition.
SCHUTZ, R. Stephen Krashen's Theory of Second Language Acquisition. In: English Made in Brazil.
Disponível em: &lt;http://sk.com.br/sk-krash.html&gt;. Acesso em: 16 jul. 2017 (adaptado).
Considerando o cartum e o excerto apresentados, avalie as asserções a seguir e a relação proposta
entre elas.
|. Quanto mais alto estiver o Filtro Afetivo do aprendiz, mais bem sucedido poderá ser o processo de
aquisição de uma segunda língua.
PORQUE
Il. Uma língua pode ser adquirida com maior facilidade e eficácia em situações comunicativas do
mundo real, permitindo que o aprendiz esteja mais aberto ao processo de input.
A respeito dessas asserções, assinale a opção correta.
O As asserções | e |l são proposições verdadeiras, e a Il é uma justificativa correta da |.
O As asserções | e Il são proposições verdadeiras, mas a Il não é uma justificativa correta da |.
O A asserção | é uma proposição verdadeira, e a Il é uma proposição falsa.
O A asserção | é uma proposição falsa, e a |l é uma proposição verdadeira.
O As asserções | e II são proposições falsas.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<ImageRegion id="r1">
	<Coords points="500,291 500,952 1577,952 1577,291"/></ImageRegion></Page></PcGts>
