<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-10-21T13:10:39</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-10-21T13:20:13</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="PROVA_DE_SECRETARIADO_EXECUTIVO-15.jpg" imageWidth="1653" imageHeight="2339">
	<SeparatorRegion id="r1">
	<Coords points="822,232 821,2150 824,2150 825,232"/></SeparatorRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r2">
	<Coords points="832,232 831,2150 833,2150 834,232"/></SeparatorRegion>
	<ImageRegion id="r0">
	<Coords points="845,391 845,957 1591,957 1591,391"/></ImageRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r119" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="850,229 1573,229 1573,1027 1574,1027 1574,1469 1573,1469 1573,1470 851,1470 851,1089 850,1089 850,1068 851,1068 851,344 850,344"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.94905">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 36
The graph bellow presents data on the sales of a company
which is facing fierce competition on the market.
Based on the information shown on the graph, mark the correct
answer below.
(A) Sales rose steeply in the beginning of April as a
consequence of the sales campaign.
(B) Sales kKkept increasing gradually until the end of the year
when the sales campaign finished.
(C) Sales declined after the introduction of larger discounts.
(D) Sales improved due to rival products launched by
competitors.
(E) Rival products were launched by competitors due to the
introduction of larger discounts.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r100" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="80,227 273,227 273,344 417,344 417,489 786,489 786,805 759,805 759,875 426,875 426,999 631,999 631,1060 577,1060 577,1180 663,1180 663,1217 738,1217 738,1253 803,1253 803,1461 802,1461 802,1462 80,1462 80,1171 78,1171 78,1144 96,1144 96,984 94,984 94,957 96,957 96,805 94,805 94,489 95,489 95,256 80,256"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.84337">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 34
Ofício nº 85/82
Belém, 4 de maio de 2006.
Ementa: Solicitação
Senhor Presidente:
Considerando a realização do Primeiro Encontro Acadêmi-
co de Secretários Executivos, patrocinado pela Federação
Nacional dos Secretários — FENASSEC — São Paulo,
vimos solicitar de V.Sa. a cessão do auditório do Grêmio
Esportivo Sabará para realização do referido encontro no
período de oito a quinze de setembro do corrente ano.
Dirigimos-lhe este pedido por sabermos do seu interesse
em colaborar também com eventos acadêmicos e culturais.
Atenciosamente,
Hipólito Campos de Oliveira
PRESIDENTE SINDICATO SECRETÁRIOS DE BELÉM
Ilmo Sr.
ALCEBÍADES SÁ FONTES
D.D. Presidente do Grêmio Esportivo Sabará
R. Tucuns, 245
Nesta
Analisando o ofício acima, conclui-se que
(A) está inadequado, por conter vários assuntos.
(B) está inadequado em virtude da linguagem utilizada.
(O) está inadequado, pois o ofício não pode ultrapassar
seis linhas de texto.
(D) está incorreto, por colocar o destinatário do ofício no
final do documento.
(E) seu formato está correto, pois o ofício pode ter disposi-
ção em bloco inteiro, bloco simples ou semibloco.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r110" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="80,1501 273,1501 273,1544 803,1544 803,1935 659,1935 659,2008 651,2008 651,2131 659,2131 659,2158 80,2158 80,1972 79,1972 79,1544 80,1544"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96586">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 35
On January 10th, John Smith celebrated his much deserved
retirement after thirty-eight years of dedicated service with the
company. John began his career in February 1969 as a trainee
secretary and over the years he worked his way up to the
position of Executive Secretary of the company s CEO (Chief
Executive Officer). Looking to the future, John will be moving
to London where he plans to divide his time between his many
grandchildren and his pastimes, which are golf and hill-walking.
Here at the Adams in-house newsletter, we hope that he will
keep in touch with the many friends that he has among the
staff and we all wish him a very happy retirement.
The purpose of this text is to
(A) communicate the promotion of an employee.
(B) announce the company retirement policy.
(O) inform staff of the departure of an employee.
(D) draw attention to new hiring procedures.
(E) advertise a position that has become vacant.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
