<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-29T19:59:22</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-29T20:19:33</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="33_LET_POR_ING_LICENCIATURA_BAIXA-23.jpg" imageWidth="1745" imageHeight="2296">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="169,244 340,244 340,312 1576,312 1576,1090 555,1090 555,1140 309,1140 309,1273 400,1273 400,1399 169,1399 169,1273 170,1273 170,1117 263,1117 263,1002 218,1002 218,914 168,914 168,739 169,739 169,461 168,461 168,312 169,312"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.95334">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 18
Over the last decades, a variety of approaches to second language acquisition (SLA) have appeared that
differ from the historically dominant one: cognitivism. Each of these approaches has contributed crucially
to what, as a result, is now a conceptually richer field. Yet while these varied approaches have enriched SLA
studies substantially, they have led to, with a few exceptions, independent and even isolated experiences.
Itis increasingly apparent that SLA is an extremely complex and multifaceted phenomenon. Exactly for this
reason, it now appears that no single theoretical perspective will allow us to understand SLA adequately.
It therefore becomes necessary for all the varied perspectives, and this includes cognitivism, to engage
one another, to “talk” to each other, to discover how they relate, differ, complement, overlap, contradict,
inform — in short, to show how they can, via comparison and contrast, lead us toward a richer, more
multidimensional understanding of SLA.
ATKINSON, D. Alternative approaches to second language acquisition. New York: Routledge, 2011 (adapted).
Taking the excerpt into account, analyse the following statements.
|. Even though various SLA approaches have contributed significantly to the understanding of the
field, they have not worked together to build this body of knowledge.
Il. The cognitivist approach denies the importance of interaction in second language classes, as the
focus of the referred approach is the development of the individuals cognitive skills.
It is important to understand all the SLA perspectives studied so far in order to get to a single
theoretical approach that could enhance second language teaching and learning.
Itis correct what is stated on
O 1, only.
O 1, only.
O IL and!ll, only.
O Il and Ill, only.
O 1, Ilandlll.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
