<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-11-04T10:35:54</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-12T03:35:34</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="relacoes_internacionais-10.jpg" imageWidth="1614" imageHeight="2167">
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="caption">
	<Coords points="80,233 1536,233 1536,264 1535,264 1535,673 1533,673 1533,860 1535,860 1535,1038 1051,1038 1051,1039 566,1039 566,1040 82,1040 82,1041 81,1041 81,861 80,861 80,676 79,676 79,291 80,291"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.92545">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 3
The Brazilian government is to give aid to two states in the north-west that have seen a recent increase in
the number of Haitian migrants. This week, the ministry for social development announced it was to give
around US$520,000 to the states of Acre and Amazonas. The first tranche of funds is expected to become
available over the next month. The continued hardship in Haiti after the devastating earthquake in January
2010 has forced thousands of people to flee to other Latin American countries in search of a better life.
The bulk of the money — around $300,000 — will support programs in Amazonas, which has recorded more
than 4,600 Haitians in the state. Acre has around 1,400 migrants. The government had already granted the
state $750,000 to support its overloaded health service. The new money will be used to implement a series
of programs through local government bodies. These will provide food and accommodation to Haitians, as
well as access to a special health service that will work independently from the national system, to meet the
specific needs of the migrants.
Disponível em &lt;http://www.theguardian.com&gt;. Acesso em: 15 jul. 2015 (adaptado).
Brazil was historically built as a country of many different migration processes. Once again, we are the
destination of new different nations: Haiti, Bolivia, Angola, Democratic Republic of Congo, among others.
Compose a text in Portuguese about the Haitian migrants and do as required.
a) Explain the historical turning point that encouraged the Haitian population to migrate to other
countries, including one domestic motivation and how it is different from other contemporary migratory
populations. (value: 5,0 points)
b) Select and describe one reason why Haitian people have chosen Brazil as one of the first options to
migrate in Latin America. (value: 5,0 points)</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
