<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-10-27T00:01:31</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-10-27T00:12:47</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="SECRETARIADO_EXECUTIVO-25.jpg" imageWidth="1637" imageHeight="2188">
	<TextRegion id="r16" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="112,581 312,581 312,656 1527,656 1527,721 1486,721 1486,807 1215,807 1215,1061 1234,1061 1234,1291 1251,1291 1251,1399 875,1399 875,1621 1095,1621 1095,1674 1170,1674 1170,1862 114,1862 114,1854 113,1854 113,1696 111,1696 111,1621 112,1621 112,1541 113,1541 113,1542 374,1542 374,1176 377,1176 377,932 375,932 375,931 374,931 374,807 155,807 155,806 154,806 154,721 112,721 112,720 111,720 111,656 112,656"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.93403">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 35:
When deciding on the relevance of information, it is important to judge the difference between
facts and value opinions. In this sense, it's important to understand the passages from reports.
Summary of Previous Report made by Purchasing Department at Interbloch HQ in July 2009
The purpose of this report is to assess the relative costs of copy
facilities based on different methods of payment. The methods
examined are:
1. Rental 2. Leasing 3. Buying
1.1. The rate of rental depends on copy volume. At 10,000
copies a month, the rate is 1.75p/per copy. A total of £175.
2.1. Ona five years lease, the monthly charge is £44.13. The
total price is £154.13.
3.1. The capital costs of buying, after tax, is £1125.60. Over five
years, that is £18.76 a month. Add running costs of 1.1p per
copy and this gives a monthly total of £128.76 for 10,000.
According to the report above is correct to state that
A) the leasing method cost will depend on the copies amount per month.
B) buying is the most expensive cost considering machine taxes.
C) buying is the cheapest cost considering the monthly total and copy volume.
D) rental is the best solution, the best method, and the cheapest.
)
E) leasing method would be an option, but rental is cheaper.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="112,169 312,169 312,235 1527,235 1527,299 1370,299 1370,404 1027,404 1027,545 1370,545 1370,516 1370,545 112,545 113,545 113,404 111,404 111,330 112,330"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.96046">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 34:
O Manual de Redação da Presidência da República (www.planalto.gov.br) estabelece as normas
para a redação de documentos oficiais.
Ao redigir um ofício, quais elementos compõem a estrutura desse tipo de documento?
A) Título, Local e data, Destinatário, Vocativo, Texto, Fecho e Assinatura.
B) Vocativo, Local e data, Destinatário, Texto, Fecho e Assinatura.
C) Título, Local e data, Destinatário, Texto, Fecho e Assinatura.
D) Título, Local e data, Destinatário, Vocativo, Texto e Assinatura.
E) Local e data, Destinatário, Vocativo, Texto, Fecho e Assinatura.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
