<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-10-27T00:01:19</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-10-27T00:12:08</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="SECRETARIADO_EXECUTIVO-26.jpg" imageWidth="1637" imageHeight="2188">
	<ImageRegion id="r4">
	<Coords points="1009,383 1008,696 1359,697 1360,384"/></ImageRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="112,169 311,169 311,245 517,245 517,315 558,315 558,316 880,316 880,431 947,431 947,522 1004,522 1004,750 1403,750 1403,887 1406,887 1406,1144 1132,1144 1132,1254 1052,1254 1052,1423 832,1423 832,1538 1006,1538 1006,1568 1051,1568 688,1568 688,1632 274,1632 274,1914 112,1914 112,1913 111,1913 111,1602 114,1602 114,1253 113,1253 113,1252 112,1252 112,1225 217,1225 217,1166 234,1166 234,887 235,887 235,733 234,733 234,273 113,273 113,272 112,272"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.94602">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 36:
Read the article about eBay.
Breaking into new markets
A business model for eccommerce?
eBay, the world's leading online auctioneer, has
a business model that definitely suits the Internet.
Thanks to many clever search features, it can match
up sellers and buyers of even the most unfamiíliar r
items. And because of its smart cost and revenue ,
structure (it charges a modes commission on each 4
transaction and does not store goods), eBay has
been one of the most consistently profitable
e-commerce businesses. In the first quarter, its net income more than doubled, to
$104.2m, on revenues of $476m. This was partly due to eBay's acquisition of PayPal,
a payments business, last year.
Taking out the effects of that deal, sales were up by 56% over the previous year. One
of eBay's greatest strengths, however, is also one of the biggest risks it faces. lts
business, like any marketplace, is a natural monopoly, and so once it is established, it
is pretty hard for a newcomer to challenge it. This has already aroused the interest of
America's Department of Justice. It took no action after an investigation a couple of
years ago, but some think it will be tempted to take another look as eBay expands.
http://digitalenterprise.org/models/models.html
Now read these statements and decide whether they are True or False.
IL
II.
IM.
IV.
V.
VI.
eBay is regarded as the top online auction company.
The company buys goods and holds them before reselling them.
lt makes a large profit on every deal.
eBay has only just started to make a profit.
eBay has recently bought a payments business.
The US Department of Justice has tried to stop eBay trading.
The only alternative that is CORRECT is
A) IevV.
B) Ie.
Cc) MelV.
D) MelvV.
E) IVevV.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
