<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2019-07-15/pagecontent.xsd">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator></Creator>
	<Created>2020-10-21T01:18:45</Created>
	<LastChange>2020-11-13T22:14:07</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="QUIMICA-12.jpg" imageWidth="1653" imageHeight="2339">
	<TextRegion id="r13" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="80,1272 1560,1272 1560,1823 1573,1823 1573,2044 80,2044"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.94076">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 19
Researchers in Minnesota have shown that olefins can be produced from vegetable-oil-derived biodiesel using methods that are
more environmentally friendly than conventional methods.
The researchers have shown that soy-based biodiesel can be oxidized to valuable olefins efficiently and fairly selectively. The
reaction is conducted in an autothermal catalytic reactor, in which heat is supplied by oxidation reactions, not by external
heaters.
To carry out the oxidation process, the Minnesota group uses an automotive fuel injector to spray droplets of biodiesel, which
consists of methyl oleate, methy1 linoleate, and related compounds, onto the walls of the reactor where the droplets vaporize.
A mixture of the organic material and air is then passed over a catalyst that contains a few percent of rhodium and cerium
supported on alumina.
By adjusting the ratio of biodiesel to oxygen (C/O) in the feed stream, the team is able to control the oxidation process and
reactor conditions, such as catalyst temperature, and thereby tune the product distribution. For example, at a C/O ratio of
roughly 1.3, the reaction yields about 25% ethylene and smaller concentrations of propylene, 1-butene, and 1-pentene. In
contrast, at a C/O ratio of 0.9, the product stream consists mainly of hydrogen and CO.
The researchers report that at all C/O ratios, the process yields less than 13% CO, (an unwanted product). They add that the
catalyst remains stable and resists deactivation by carbon buildup even under extreme conditions.
(Adapted from Chemical and Engeneering News, 83(1),10, 2005)
De acordo com o texto acima, é possível concluir:
(A) Atransformação do biodiesel em olefinas se passa na ausência de calor.
(B) Combustíveis automotivos foram utilizados na produção de biodiesel.
(C) A umidade do ar desativa o catalisador de ródio e cério suportado em alumínio.
(D) A composição final da mistura de olefinas é dependente da proporção biodiesel/oxigênio usada como material de partida.
(E) Ao aumentar a proporção de biodiesel em relação ao oxigênio, o produto da reação consiste basicamente de hidrogênio e CO.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="80,263 1573,263 1573,365 1151,365 1151,479 938,479 938,512 377,512 377,760 1458,760 1458,821 80,821 80,737 79,737 79,385 80,385"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.89178">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 17
Uma indústria necessita estocar solução de cloreto de níquel 1mol/L, a 25 ºC, e dispõe dos tanques X, Y, Z e W, relacionados
a seguir.
Tanque X: construído em ferro e revestido internamente com borracha a base de ebonite.
Tanque Y: construído em aço inoxidável tipo 304 (liga: ferro 74%, cromo 18%, níquel 8%).
Tanque Z: construído em ferro galvanizado.
Tanque W: construído em ferro revestido com estanho eletrodepositado.
Dados:
Ni? /NIº Eº=-0,25V
Zn'?/Znº Eº=-0,76V
Fe*?/Feº Eº=-0,44 V
Sn*º/Snº Eº =- 0,14 V
Cr /Cr Eº=-0,74V
Dentre esses tanques, quais são adequados para estocar a solução em questão?
(A) XeZ (B) Xe W (C) YeZz (D) Ye W (E) Ze W</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords points="80,865 111,865 111,900 1573,900 1573,994 707,994 707,1170 1490,1170 1490,1238 80,1238 80,1170 81,1170 81,994 79,994 79,900 80,900"/>
	<TextEquiv conf="0.73770">
	<Unicode>QUESTÃO 18
O alumínio é o terceiro elemento mais abundante na crosta terrestre depois do oxigênio e do silício. Tem grande aplicação
industrial, sendo utilizado na fabricação de recipientes, embalagens, na construção civil e na indústria aeroespacial, entre
outros usos. Com relação às propriedades do alumínio, pode-se afirmar que:
I - formao íon AIº* que é paramagnético;
II - seuíon Alº* tem forte efeito polarizante;
III - pode ser obtido pela eletrólise ígnea da bauxita;
IV - seus haletos agem como Ácidos de Lewis.
São corretas apenas as afirmações:
(A) II e IV. (B) III e IV. (C) I, II e III. (D) I, II e IV. (E) II, III e IV.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
